Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: Bertha Spafford Vester with Lowell Thomas and Frances Ryan Thomas, 1965; 7 (Box 1562)
    - [Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas, and Bertha Spafford], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas, and Bertha Spafford], 2
    - [Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas and Bertha Spafford looking at flowers], 3
    - [Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas and Bertha Spafford looking at flowers], 4
  - Subject files: Veterans of the French Foreign Legion (Maurice A. Hammoneau), 1934; 8 (Box 1562)
    - [Portrait of a woman (?)], 1
    - [Maurice A. Hammoneau, verteran of the French Foreign Legion], 2
  - Subject files: Vicariate Apostolic of Wewak, New Guinea, 1967; 9 (Box 1562)
    - [Two men playing instruments in New Guinea], 1
    - Note: [Letter to Lowell Thomas from Leo Arkfeld S.V.D. Bishop of Wewak concerning New Guinea], 2
  - Subject files: Victor Museum, 1949; 10 (Box 1562)
    - [Two people standing outside a house], 1
    - [A house-Victor Museum (?)], 2
  - Subject files: Hans von Kaltenborn, circa 1930s; 11 (Box 1562)
    - [Hans von Kaltenborn, second from right in front row, Lowell Thomas third from right in front row], 1
    - Verso: LT with H V Kaltenborn, 1-verso
  - Subject files: Count Felix von Luckner, 1920s - 1962; 12 (Box 1562)
    - [Count Felix von Luckner with Lowell Thomas, Jr., center], 1
    - [Count Felix von Luckner with Lowell Thomas, Jr.], 2
    - Caption: With my love to you both, Yours, Ingeborg[?]; Note: With my love to you both, Yours, Ingeborg[?], 3
    - Verso: Merry Christmas + a Happy New Year, 3-verso
    - Note: With my love to you both, Yours, Ingeborg[?], 4
    - Newspaper clipping after his landing in St. Francisco, 5
    - Verso: Newspaper clipping after his landing in St. Francisco, 5-verso
    - Departure of Hans Hoss to his under water expedition from Hamburg, 1960?, 6
    - Verso: Departure of Hans Hoss to his under water expedition from Hamburg, 1960?, 6-verso
    - [Departure of Hans Hoss to his under water expedition from Hamburg, 1960?], 7
    - Cold look in my eye as though I might have a gun on my hip and Carveth (Wells) as usual caught in the midst of making a speech. It's a pretty good picture. Wish we could have a few copies. I suppose the copies would be just as good as this one?..[Count Felix von Luckner, center], 8
    - Note: Cold look in my eye as though I might have a gun on my hip and Carveth (Wells) as usual caught in the midst of making a speech. It's a pretty good picture. Wish we could have a few copies. I suppose the copies would be just as good as this one?..[Count Felix von Luckner, center], 9
    - Goettingen, 1958?, 10
    - Verso: Goettingen, 1958?, 10-verso
    - [To Fran and Lowell with shiploads of health and good luck, from Felix; Xmas 1961], 11
    - [To Fran and Lowell with shiploads of health and good luck, from Felix; Xmas 1961], 12
    - [To Fran and Lowell with shiploads of health and good luck, from Felix; Xmas 1961], 13
    - [To Fran and Lowell with shiploads of health and good luck, from Felix; Xmas 1961], 14
    - Note: To Fran and Lowell with shiploads of health and good luck, from Felix; Xmas 1961, [rear is letter to Lowell Thomas from Felix von Luckner], [PDF], 15
    - Count Luckner, Hamburg 1962, 16
    - Note: Count Luckner, Hamburg 1962, 17
    - [Count Luckner, Hamburg 1962], 18
    - Count Luckner and the ship's cat, 19
    - Verso: Count Luckner and the ship's cat, 19-verso
    - [portrait of Count Felix von Luckner], [3 copies], 20
    - [portrait of Count Felix von Luckner], 21
    - [Lowell Thomas, Count Felix von Luckner and three unidentified men], 22
  - Subject files: Count Felix von Luckner (Caribbean cruise with the Thomases), circa 1927; 13 (Box 1562)
    - [Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas], 1
    - [Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas and Count Felix von Luckner], 2
    - [Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas and Lowell Thomas], 3
    - [Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas kneeling at left], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas and Count Felix von Luckner], 5
    - Count Luckner returns with a few fish for his honeymooners, 6
    - Verso: Count Luckner returns with a few fish for his honeymooners, 6-verso
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner on his cruise ship], 7
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner and two men looking at something], 8
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner standing with another man], 9
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner], 10
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner and a man], 11
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner on his cruise ship], 12
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner standing on his cruise ship], 13
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner standing with a man], 14
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner sharing a drink with a man on his cruise ship], 15
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner pointing at something off in the distance], 16
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner on his cruise ship], 17
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner sitting with binocilars around his neck], 18
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner posing on his cruise ship], 19
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner ponting at something], 20
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner sitting in a net on his cruise ship], 21
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner on his cruise ship], 22
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner standing with a man], 23
    - The Count ready to call on the President of Santo Domingo, 24
    - Verso: The Count ready to call on the President of Santo Domingo, 24-verso
    - The Count gets in fancy dress costume by improvising a hat from a huge West Indian sponge, 25
    - The Count gets in fancy dress costume by improvising a hat from a huge West Indian sponge, 25-verso
    - Verso: Count Felix von Luckner, 26
    - Verso: Count Felix von Luckner, 26-verso
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner pointing at something fron his cruise ship], 27
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner pointing], 28
    - [Camera crew abord a cruise ship], 29
    - [Man with pipe standing on a cruise ship], 30
    - [Deckhands on a cruise ship], 31
    - [The mast of Count Felix Von Luckner's cruise ship], 32
    - [Man standing on a cruise ship], 33
    - [Two men aboard a cruise ship], 34
    - [Guests aboard the cruise ship], 35
    - Mrs. Ward, wife of the Grange Crush King introduces the Hawaiian garb to the Caribbean, 36
    - Verso: Mrs. Ward, wife of the Grange Crush King introduces the Hawaiian garb to the Caribbean, 36-verso
    - [Woman on a cruise ship], 37
    - [A group of people sitting together on a cruise ship], 38
    - [A man and woman on a cruise ship], 39
    - Mr. and Mrs. Burt Massee ready for the christening party, 40
    - Verso: Mr. and Mrs. Burt Massee ready for the christening party, 40-verso
    - [View of another ship from the cruise ship], 41
    - [People in a net of the crusie ship], 42
    - [Self-portrait of the artisit on the Caribbean cruise], 43
    - [Artist sketching a self portrait on the cruise ship], 44
    - [Man woring with rope on the cruise ship], 45
    - [Men working on the cruise ship], 46
    - [People playing music on the cruise ship], 47
  - Subject files: Count Felix von Luckner (Caribbean cruise with the Thomases), circa 1927; 14 (Box 1562)
    - [Group of people on the cruise ship], 1
    - [Man taking a photograph of a ship from a cruise ship], 2
    - [People on the chains and net of a cruise ship], 3
    - [Woman swinging on the cruise ship], 4
    - [Two men standing on the cruise ship], 5
    - [Man talking to a group on the cruise ship], 6
    - McClelland Barclay the artist at work, 7
    - Verso: McClelland Barclay the artist at work, 7-verso
    - The rigging of the S.S. Mopelia, 8
    - Verso: The rigging of the S.S. Mopelia, 8-verso
    - [Deckhands working on the cruise ship], 9
    - The Bo's'n, old Charlie, who had sailed round and round the globe so many times that he lost count, 10
    - Verso: The Bo's'n, old Charlie, who had sailed round and round the globe so many times that he lost count, 10-verso
    - Old Charlie, the Bo'sun, 11
    - Verso: Old Charlie, the Bo'sun, 11-verso
    - One of the camera men goes native, 12
    - Verso: One of the camera men goes native, 12-verso
    - [Man holding two sharks], 13
    - [Man sitting on the chains of a cruise ship], 14
    - [Man standing on a cruise ship], 15
    - [Four men talking on a cruise ship], 16
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner sitting with a woman on a cruise ship], 17
    - [The cruise ship heading to the Caribbean], 18
    - [Man working on the sail of a cruise ship], 19
    - [View of the cruise ship], 20
    - [A group of people on the deck of a cruise ship], 21
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner standing on a cruise ship with another man], 22
    - [A man holding a parrot on a cruise ship], 23
    - [Man rowing in a life raft], 24
    - McClelland Barclay's speed boat, the Dog Fish, which was taken along as the tender on the [Mopelia], 25
    - Verso: McClelland Barclay's speed boat, the Dog Fish, which was taken along as the tender on the [Mopelia], 25-verso
    - [McClelland Barclay's speed boat, the Dog Fish], 26
    - [McClelland Barclay's speed boat, the Dog Fish], 27
    - [unknown man women and boy], 28
    - [Military men marching], 29
    - [People on shore, the cruise ship moored at sea], 30
    - [A local house and family in the Caribbean], 31
    - [A house in thr Caribbean], 32
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner (?) and two others in the Caribbean], 33
    - [Four men standing in front of a carving in the Caribbean], 34
    - [Two men talking aboard the cruise ship], 35
    - [A group of people looking at something], 36
    - The army of Santo Domingo honors Dan Edwards, 37
    - Verso: The army of Santo Domingo honors Dan Edwards, 37-verso
    - [Members of the Santo Domingo army], 38
    - [Men of the Santo Domingo army], 39
    - [Two men], 40
    - Gen Dan Edwards, left, and General Trujillo, commander in chief of the army of Santo Domingo, 41
    - Verso: Gen Dan Edwards, left, and General Trujillo, commander in chief of the army of Santo Domingo, 41-verso
    - [General Dan Edwards and General Trujillo], 42
    - Our pilot at San Salvador whom we had to fish out of the sea when he fell overboard, 43
    - Verso: Our pilot at San Salvador whom we had to fish out of the sea when he fell overboard, 43-verso
    - [General Dan Edwards and General Trujillo], 44
    - [Two men holding up a painting], 45
    - The Dominican Friar of San Salvador in front of the portrait of Columbus which adorns the wall of his little chapel, 46
    - Verso: The Dominican Friar of San Salvador in front of the portrait of Columbus which adorns the wall of his little chapel, 46-verso
  - Subject files: Count Felix von Luckner (Caribbean cruise with the Thomases), circa 1927; 15 (Box 1562)
    - [Caribbean cruise ship], 1
    - [Caribbean cruise ship], 2
    - [Caribbean cruise ship], 3
    - [Caribbean cruise ship], 4
    - [Caribbean cruise ship], 5
    - [Caribbean cruise ship], 6
    - [Caribbean cruise ship], 7
    - [Caribbean cruise ship], 8
    - A rare experience at sea these days. Our old windy [illegible] passes another ship under full spread of canvas., 9
    - Verso: A rare experience at sea these days. Our old windy [illegible] passes another ship under full spread of canvas., 9-verso
    - S.S. Mopelia, 10
    - Verso: S.S. Mopelia, 10-verso
    - S.S. Mopelia, 11
    - Verso: S.S. Mopelia, 11-verso
    - [S.S. Mopelia], 12
    - S.S. Mopelia, 13
    - Verso: S.S. Mopelia, 13-verso
    - S.S. Mopelia, 14
    - Verso: S.S.Mopelia, 14-verso
    - [S.S. Mopelia], 15
    - [Sketch of the sail of a ship], 16
  - Subject files: Count Felix von Luckner (Caribbean cruise with the Thomases) [duplicates], circa 1927; 16 (Box 1562)
    - [Count Felix von Luckner holding a fish on a cruise ship], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas and Count Felix von Luckner], 2
    - The camera men swing into action as we approach the landing place of Columbus at San Salvador, 3
    - Verso: The camera men swing into action as we approach the landing place of Columbus at San Salvador, 3-verso
    - [unknown man women and boy], 4
    - [Santo Domingo army], 5
    - [Woman on a Caribbean cruise ship], 6
    - [Cruise guests gathered to look at something], 7
    - [Count Felix von Luckner and two others in the Caribbean], 8
    - [Four men standing by a carving in the Caribbean], 9
    - [Man with a pipe on a cruise ship], 10
    - [Count Felix von Luckner on his cruise ship], 11
    - [Woman dressed as a hulan dancer on a cruise ship], 12
    - [Man dressed at a pirate on a cruise ship], 13
    - [Man standing on a cruise ship], 14
    - [General Dan Edwards and General Trujillo], 15
    - [S.S. Mopelia (?)], 16
    - [Count Felix von Luckner], 17
    - [Count Felix von Luckner on his cruise ship], 18
    - [Two guests on a cruise ship], 19
    - [Count Felix von Luckner standing with a man], 20
    - [A group of people sitting on a cruise ship], 21
    - [Cruise guests on the deck of the ship], 22
    - [Felix von Luckner standing with a man], 23
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner with something strange on his head, 24
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner sharing a drink with a man], 25
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner sharing a drink with a man], 26
    - Count Felix Von Luckner sharing a drink with a man], 27
    - Count Luckner, 28
    - Verso: Count Luckner, 28-verso
    - Gen. Dan Edwards leading a parade of the army of Santo Domingo, 29
    - Verso: Gen. Dan Edwards leading a parade of the army of Santo Domingo, 29-verso
    - [Count Felix von Luckner], 30
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner and a woman], 31
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner sitting in the net on a cruise ship, 32
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner pointing at something], 33
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner sitting in the net on a cruise ship], 34
    - [Man on cruise ship working], 35
    - [Count Felix von Luckner standing with a man], 36
    - [View of a ship from the cruise ship], 37
    - [Guests in the net on a cruise ship], 38
    - [Man working with rope on a cruise ship], 39
    - [Man taking a photo from the cruise ship of another ship], 40
    - [People gathered on the deck of the cruise ship], 41
    - [Two men], 42
    - [Sketch of a ship], 43
    - [S.S. Mopelia (?)], 44
    - [S.S. Mopelia (?)], 45
    - [Man rowing in the life raft], 46
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner standing with another man], 47
    - [Man holding two sharks], 48
    - [Man on cruise ship telling a story], 49
    - [Woman swinging on cruise ship], 50
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner pointing to something off in the distance], 51
    - [Count Felix von Luckner posing on his cruise ship], 52
    - [Count Felix Von Luckner standing with a man], 53
    - [S.S. Mopelia (?)], 54
  - Subject files: Count Felix von Luckner (miscellaneous), circa 1930s; 17 (Box 1562)
    - Funeral of Count v. Luckner, Michael's Kirche, Hamburg, 1
    - Verso: Funeral of Count v. Luckner, Michael's Kirche, Hamburg, 1-verso
    - Michael's Kirche, Hamburg [funeral of Count Felix von Luckner], 2
    - Verso: Michael's Kirche, Hamburg [funeral of Count Felix von Luckner], 2-verso
    - Gov. Paul Dudley White with my "two wheel drive bicycle", 3
    - Verso: Gov. Paul Dudley White with my "two wheel drive bicycle", 3-verso
    - Last photograph on the Kaiser's 80th birthday, 4
    - Verso: Last photograph on the Kaiser's 80th birthday, 4-verso
    - Graduation speech for Air Force Cadets in Oxford, Ohio, 5
    - Verso: Graduation speech for Air Force Cadets in Oxford, Ohio, 5-verso
    - Luneburger Heide with Max Schmeling and his wife (Annie Ondra), 6
    - Verso: Luneburger Heide with Max Schmeling and his wife (Annie Ondra), 6-verso
    - Zandvort [Zandvoort] Holland, 1934, 7
    - Verso: Zandvort [Zandvoort] Holland, 1934, 7-verso
    - The horses were a gift from John Ringling North. While riding them I lost my angina pectoris, 40 years old. Had to talk about it in the "Sorbonne" in Paris. There I met Dr. Paul Dudley white. 1950 (Ier Congres Mondial De Cardiologie) and we have been friends since, 8
    - Verso: The horses were a gift from John Ringling North. While riding them I lost my angina pectoris, 40 years old. Had to talk about it in the "Sorbonne" in Paris. There I met Dr. Paul Dudley white. 1950 (Ier Congres Mondial De Cardiologie) and we have been friends since, 8-verso
    - Mrs. [?], Roman riding, 9
    - Verso: Mrs. [?], Roman riding, 9-verso
    - By McClelland Barclay, Sept. 1929, 10
    - Verso: By McClelland Barclay, Sept. 1929, 10-verso
    - Ingeborg Countess Luckner; Painted by Edward Cuenel; New York, Dec. 1932, 11
    - Verso: Ingeborg Countess Luckner; Painted by Edward Cuenel; New York, Dec. 1932, 11-verso
    - [Drawn portrait of Felix von Luckner, 1928, 2 copies], 12
    - [Drawn portrait of Count Felix von Luckner, 1928], 13
    - [S.S. Mopelia (?)], 14
    - [S.S. Mopelia (?)], 15
    - [S.S. Mopelia (?)], 16
    - [S.S. Mopelia (?)], 17
    - [S.S. Mopelia (?)], 18
    - Caption: The Story of a Flag, Long May it Wave, 19
  Box 1563
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: Frieda Ward, Jerusalem [contact sheets], circa 1968; 1 (Box 1563)
    - [sheet of 7 photographs of Frieda Ward, Jerusalem], 1
    - [sheet of 12 photographs of Frieda Ward, Jerusalem], 2
    - [sheet of 30 photographs of Frieda Ward, Jerusalem], 3
  - Subject files: Brad Washburn, 1947 - 1955; 2 (Box 1563)
    - Barbara and Bradford Washburn on top of McKinley-June 6, 1947. First Ascent by a woman; also first ascent by man and wife; Photograph by Bradford Washburn, 1
    - Verso: Barbara and Bradford Washburn on top of McKinley-June 6, 1947. First Ascent by a woman; also first ascent by man and wife; Photograph by Bradford Washburn, 1-verso
    - Surveying McKinley from the top of a nearby peak-1947; Photograph by Bradford Washburn, 2
    - Verso: Surveying McKinley from the top of a nearby peak-1947; Photograph by Bradford Washburn, 2-verso
    - Bradford Washburn in 1955 with big 24x8x10 camera photographing Mt. McKinley from the Southeast; Photograph by Bradford Washburn, 3
    - Verso: Bradford Washburn in 1955 with big 24x8x10 camera photographing Mt. McKinley from the Southeast; Photograph by Bradford Washburn, 3-verso
  - Subject files: Waterfall, undated; 3 (Box 1563)
    - [Waterfall], [2 copies], 1
    - Is this LT Jr.-in South America, 2
    - Verso: Is this LT Jr.-in South America, 2-verso
  - Subject files: Carveth Wells, undated; 4 (Box 1563)
    - Lapland salmon and Carveth Wells, 60 pounder, 1
    - Verso: Lapland salmon and Carveth Wells, 60 pounder, 1-verso
  - Subject files: Carveth Wells (Africa), undated; 5 (Box 1563)
    - [Osa Johnson, right], 1
    - [with Explorer's Club flag], 2
    - [Man with a lion cub in Africa], 3
    - [An playing with a lion], 4
    - [A lion in the grass], 5
    - [Scenery in Africa], 6
    - rhino by ant hill, 7
    - Verso: rhino by ant hill, 7-verso
    - Rhino in East Africa, 8
    - Verso: Rhino in East Africa, 8-verso
    - [Rhino in the plains of Africa], 9
    - [A giraffe in Africa], 10
    - [A giraffe in Africa], 11
    - [A tribal person's headdress], 12
    - [A tribesperson], 13
    - [A tribesman], 14
    - [A tribal person's interesting hea wear], 15
    - [A tribal person's earrings], 16
  - Subject files: Linton Wells, undated; 6 (Box 1563)
    - Linton Wells, 1
    - Verso: Linton Wells, 1-verso
    - Linton Wells, 2
    - Verso: Linton Wells, 2-verso
  - Subject files: Whitewater, Ohio [Uncle Ira Thomas's ranch], circa 1932; 7 (Box 1563)
    - Vulcans Cottage. Showing the East & North side of Dwelling at Whitewater; as of August 1932, 1
    - Verso: Vulcans Cottage. Showing the East & North side of Dwelling at Whitewater; as of August 1932, 1-verso
    - Vulcans Cottage. Whitewater, Indiana. Showing West and South side of cottage before the spouting and eaves put on, otherwise no change; 1932, August, 2
    - Verso: Vulcans Cottage. Whitewater, Indiana. Showing West and South side of cottage before the spouting and eaves put on, otherwise no change; 1932, August, 2-verso
    - Showing the outbuilding on the same lot as of August 1932. The wire fence is around the well which has been dry for a long time, 3
    - Verso: Showing the outbuilding on the same lot as of August 1932. The wire fence is around the well which has been dry for a long time, 3-verso
    - Woodington, Darke County, Ohio; June 1932, 4
    - Verso: Woodington, Darke County, Ohio; June 1932, 4-verso
    - Note: [Letter to Lowell Thomas from his uncle Ira], 5
  - Subject files: Jim Whittaker [color photographs], circa 1963; 8 (Box 1563)
    - Jim Whitacker [sic], who led American Mt. Everest expedition [Jim Whittaker, right, Lowell Thomas, second from right], 1
    - Verso: Jim Whitacker [sic], who led American Mt. Everest expedition [Jim Whittaker, right, Lowell Thomas, second from right], 1-verso
    - [Jim Whittaker, right, Lowell Thomas, second from right], 2
  - Subject files: Sir Hubert Wilkins, undated; 9 (Box 1563)
    - [Man wearing a fur coat], 1
    - [A man in a fur coat], 2
    - [Child in a fur coat], 3
    - [Mother and child in Alaska (?)], 4
    - [Man wearing fur], 5
    - [Man in coat holding a model of a canoe], 6
    - [Man standing in a fur coat], 7
    - [Woman wearing a fur coat], 8
    - [Man wearing a fur coat], 9
    - [An airplane landing in water], 10
    - [Snowy mountains], 11
    - [Birds-eye-view map of the North Pole], 12
    - [An airplane landing in water], 13
    - Caption: Sunset on the Slopes of South Georgia, 14
    - Caption: The Pylon Way from Aloft, 15
    - Caption: Loading Sea-Elephants' Blubber at Cape Lookout, Elephant Island, 16
    - Caption: A Mammoth Berg Rising like a Castle of Gleaming Marble above the Pack. Two Figures can be Seen near the Base of the Icecliff on the Left., 17
    - Caption: Sugar Top Mountain-Part of the Allardyce Range South Georgia, 18
    - Caption: The Fo'c'stle Head of the "Aurora" Sheathed with Ice After a Blizzard in Commonwealth Bay., 19
    - [Aerial view of snoy mountains], 20
    - [Snow-covered mountains], 21
    - [Snowy mountains], 22
    - [Mountains covered in snow], 23
    - [Snowy mountain landscape], 24
    - [Snowy mountains], 25
    - [Snowy mountains by the ocean], 26
    - Caption: "We Were the Only Black Speck in that Dazzling Panorama of Chaotic Icefields.", 27
    - Caption: Heading South Through Open Pack, 28
    - Caption: A Mid-summer Scene in the Boat Harbour, Main Base. Weddell Seals Basking on "Pancake" Floes., 29
    - Caption: The "Aurora" During a Calm Evening in Commonwealth Bay. In the Background the Crevassed Slopes of Adelie Land Rise to a Heigt of Two Thousand Feet., 30
    - [Two men looking out a window], 31
    - [Aerial view of snowy mountains], 32
    - [View of snow-covered mountains from a ship], 33
    - [A group of native peoples], 34
    - [A native child], 35
    - [Man bundled up in the cold weather], 36
    - [Man looking out a window], 37
    - Caption: Emperor Penguins on the Floe: A Still Evening in the Pack, 38
    - Caption: A Pressure Ridge in Active Formation; The Process of "Rafting.", 39
    - Caption: Finner Whales in the Open Pack. The Far Whale has Just "Blown," the Near One is Just About to "Sound.", 40
    - Caption: "As we Descended, the Ice Grew into a Maze of Crevasses with Yawning Abysses on Every Side. It was Impassable.", 41
    - [Crowd gathered around a derigible], 42
    - [Aerial view of snowy mountains], 43
    - [Mountains and the ocean], 44
    - [Snowy mountain tops], 45
  - Subject files: Sir Hubert Wilkins, undated; 10 (Box 1563)
    - [Child in a fur coat], 1
    - [Man standing outside in a heavy coat], 2
    - [Man with a fur hood smiling], 3
    - [Portrait of a man in glasses], 4
    - [Person wearing a fur coat], 5
    - [Three men boarding a plane], 6
    - [Airplane on the runway], 7
    - [Man in a large fur coat], 8
    - [Man sitting on the nose of a plane], 9
    - [People getting supplies off a train of sleds (?)], 10
    - [Native Alaskan man], 11